欢迎来到11号星际基地，舰长，准将正等着见您
Welcome to Starbase 11, captain. The commodore is waiting to see you.
他很好奇您为什么突然转向来这里
He's curious why you suddenly changed course and came here.
我们收到子空间信息，要求我们立刻转向这里
We received a subspace message asking us to divert here immediately.
基地没有发送任何信息，舰长
This base sent no message, captain.
吉姆，我不理解
Oh, Jim, I just can't understand this.
史波克收到一条这个基地的信息
Mr. Spock received a transmission from this starbase,
来自进取号前任舰长派克
a message from former commander of the Enterprise, Fleet Captain Pike,
需要我们紧急转向这里
urgently requesting that we divert here.
- 不可能 - 如果我的大副说他收到…
- Impossible. - If my first officer states he received--
- 吉姆，我不是怀疑谁 - 约瑟，我…
- Jim, I’m not doubting anyone's word. - Jose, I--
- 我是说这不可能 - 为什么？
- I'm simply telling you it's impossible. - Why?
你不知道？你真的不知道？
You don't know? You actually don't know
派克舰长怎么了？
what's happened to Captain Pike?
他的传言在子空间流传了好几个月
There's been subspace chatter about it for months.
很抱歉，我不得不让你们见见他了
I'm sorry to have to be the one to show you.
他在楼上的医务科
He's upstairs in the medical section.
安静 重症监护室
你见过克里斯·派克吗？
You ever met Chris Pike?
他被提升为舰队指挥官时见过面
We met when he was promoted to fleet captain.
当时和你年纪相仿
About your age.
- 高大帅气，充满活力 - 他走后我接手了进取号
- A big, handsome man, vital, active. - I took over the Enterprise from him.
史波克在他手下干了好几年
Spock served with him for several years.
11年又4个月零5天
Eleven years, four months, five days.
他怎么了，准将？
What's his problem, commodore?
在一艘老旧的J级训练舰上视察的时候
Inspection tour of a cadet vessel, old class-J starship.
一块挡板破裂了
One of the baffle plates ruptured.
德耳塔射线？
The delta rays?
他救出了那些活着的学生
He went in, bringing out all those kids that were still alive.
你们要做好心理准备
Just wanted you gentlemen to be prepared.
派克舰长？
Captain Pike?
舰长
Captain.
还记得这几位先生吗，他们想见你
You remember these gentlemen. They wanted to visit you.
闪两次表示“不”
Two flashes mean "no."
我还以为你会特别对待他们
I thought you might make an exception for them.
非常抱歉，先生们
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
克里斯，如果有什么我能帮上忙的…
Chris, if there's anything I can do for you...
派克舰长…
Captain Pike...
我能留下一会儿吗？
...may I remain for a moment?
你知道我为什么来，舰长？
You know why I’ve come, captain.
以最大曲速飞往那个地方，只要6天
It's only six days away at maximum warp,
而且我已经都准备好了
and I have it well planned.
我以前从没有违背过你的命令，舰长
I have never disobeyed your orders before, captain.
但是这一次，我必须这样
But this time, I must.
我知道，这就相当于背叛和谋反
I know. I know it is treachery, and it's mutiny.
但我必须这样做
But I must do this.
我没有选择
I have no choice.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：LPF
校对：喜马拉雅 Micezhang xjCGI
第一季第十一集
困兽之斗（上）
我再说一遍，约瑟
Once more, Jose.
史波克说他收到这里发给我们的信息
Spock stated he received a message for us to come here.
他的日志里有记录，有这证据就够了
He entered same in his log. That's all the proof I require.
那些记录磁带显示了什么？
And what do those record tapes show?
没有来自这里的信息
No message sent from here.
你的星舰也没有收到信息
No message received by your vessel.
我认为那些磁带被故意修改了
Then I suggest the record tapes have been deliberately changed.
计算机专家可以修改磁带
A computer expert can change record tapes,
复制声音，修改内容，或者删除
duplicate voices, say anything, say nothing.
事实是你大副的前任长官住院了
The fact remains that your first officer's former captain is hospitalized,
重度伤残，在基地疗养
horribly injured, at this base.
这个大副似乎是唯一
And that same first officer seems to be the only one
- 听到这信息的人 - 如果他想见派克舰长
- who heard that message-- - If he wanted to see Captain Pike,
他大可申请离开
he could've requested a leave.
当然，确实如此
Well, that's true, of course.
谁想让我们转向这里？
Who would want to divert us here?
在我们巡逻的宇宙区域没有异常
There's no trouble in the space sector we're patrolling now,
没有外星人入侵
no alien problems.
计算机中心
Computer centre.
这里是洪保德主管，长官
Chief Humboldt here, sir.
你重新检查过当时
Have you rechecked all the record tapes
所有的记录磁带吗？
on the date in question?
- 是的，长官 - 会不会…
- Yes, sir. - Is there any way at all
发送过一条信息而我们不知道？
a message could've been sent without us knowing it?
不可能，我们检查并复查了所有可能的地方
Negative. We've checked and double-checked everything possible.
好吧，那就开始检查不可能的地方
All right. Start checking the impossible.
门德兹完闭
Mendez out.
噢，我有介绍过派珀小姐吗？这是寇克舰长，派珀小姐
Oh, have I introduced Miss Piper, Jim? This is Captain Kirk, Miss Piper.
我一眼就认出了舰长
I recognized the captain immediately.
我们共同的朋友说起过你，先生，记得海伦·约翰松上尉吗？
A mutual friend described you, sir. Lieutenant Helen Johannson?
海伦描述说…
Helen described...
她只说认识你，先生
She merely mentioned she knew you, sir.
你有事汇报吗，派珀小姐？
You have something to report, Miss Piper?
是的，长官
Oh, yes, sir.
我们的调查没多少收获，准将
I'm afraid our investigation turned up very little, commodore.
当然，史波克与派克舰长共事多年
There is, of course, Mr. Spock's years of service with Captain Pike,
表明他非常忠诚于他的前任长官
indications of his extreme loyalty to this former commander--
一个瓦肯人不会不忠，就像不呼吸就无法生存
A Vulcan can no sooner be disloyal than he can exist without breathing.
这适用于他的前任长官，也适用于现任
That goes for his present commander as well as his past.
我们必须考虑任何可能性，先生
We're forced to consider every possibility, sir.
我们可以确定派克舰长没有发送任何消息
We can be certain Captain Pike could not have sent a message.
按他的情况，每时每刻都被监视
In his condition, he's under observation every minute of every day.
而且完全不能活动，吉姆
And totally unable to move, Jim.
他的轮椅可以按照他的想法活动
His wheelchair is constructed to respond to his brain waves.
他能让它转向，向前或向后移动一点
Oh, he can turn it, move it forwards or backward slightly.
也能通过灯光闪烁表达是或否
Through the flashing light, he can say yes or no.
但只有这些，吉姆
But that's it, Jim.
这家伙只能做到这些
That's as much as that poor devil can do.
他的脑子像我们一样活跃
His mind is as active as yours and mine,
但它被僵硬的躯体困住了，无能为力
but it's trapped inside a useless, vegetating body.
机器维持着他的生命
He's kept alive mechanically,
一个电池驱动的心脏
a battery-driven heart.
他甚至没办法
Then there's no way he could even have asked
让别人发送信息吗？
for that message to be sent?
星际基地指挥部
Starbase Operations.
星际基地指挥部，星际基地指挥部
Starbase Operations. Starbase Operations.
星际基地指挥部，星际基地指挥部呼叫进取号
Starbase Operations starbase Operations to Enterprise.
准备接收新命令，进取号
Stand by to receive new orders, Enterprise.
星际基地指挥部呼叫，汉森先生
Starbase Operation, Mr. Hanson.
星际基地指挥部呼叫进取号，准备接收新命令
starbase Operations to Enterprise. Stand by to receive new orders.
这些命令直接输入计算机
They are to be fed directly into the ship's computers.
这是最高机密的紧急行动
This is top-secret and scrambled.
进取号待命
Enterprise standing by.
请求确认
Request confirmation.
进取号呼叫星际基地，请求确认
Enterprise to starbase. Request confirmation.
先生，这里是禁区，你在干什么？
Sir, this is a security area. What are you doing?
我有安全许可，主管
I have security clearance, chief.
谁授予的？我没有得到通知
Who gave you clearance? I haven't been notified.
你在交叉联接…
You're cross-circuiting the--
这是谁的磁带？
Whose tapes are these?
重复一遍，进取号呼叫星际基地，命令收到
Repeat, Enterprise to starbase. Orders received.
我们需要舰长的执行确认
We need operating confirmation from the ship's captain.
请回话，星际基地，请回话，寇克舰长
Come in, starbase. Come in, Captain Kirk.
我是寇克舰长，确定执行，乌乎拉小姐
This is Captain Kirk. You have confirmation, Miss Uhura.
我是汉森，舰长
Hanson here, captain.
我们的目的地信息被加密后输入了计算机
Our destination has been scramble-fed into ship's computers.
不知道目的地，我怎么掌舵？
How can I handle the helm if I don't know where we're going?
史波克先生在我旁边，他将回答所有疑问，寇克完闭
Mr. Spock is with me here. He'll answer all questions. Kirk out.
我是史波克
This is Mr. Spock.
此次航行由计算机掌舵，汉森先生
The ship's computers will handle the helm on this voyage, Mr. Hanson.
自动计算并设定航线
Course will be computed and set automatically.
不许你跟舰员或基地人员讨论此事
You will not discuss this with ship's crew or starbase personnel.
- 你明白了吗？ - 明白，长官
- Do you read? - Acknowledged, sir.
待命，我们将在一小时内飞离轨道
Stand by. We'll warp out of orbit in one hour.
他一直闪灯表示“不”，不什么？
He keeps blinking "no." No to what?
我试图问他，但他焦急得快晕过去了
I've tried questioning him. He's almost agitated himself into a coma.
- 他能活多久？ - 和我们一样
- How long will he live? - As long as any of us.
依靠大量的药物
Blast medicine anyway.
我们已经可以植入所有的人体器官
We've learned to tie into every human organ in the body except one:
除了大脑，而大脑是生命之所在
the brain. And the brain is what life is all about.
现在，他能像我们一样思考
Now, that man can think any thought that we can.
和我们一样爱，期望，梦想
And love, hope, dream as much as we can.
但他不能表达，也没人能知道他的想法
But he can't reach out, and no one can reach in.
- 他一直表达“否” - 否什么？
- He keeps blinking "no." - No to what?
他们要问他几天，几个星期
They could question him for days, weeks,
才能蒙对
before they stumble on the right thing.
老骨头
Bones...
这是否与史波克有关？
...could this have anything to do with Spock?
我不明白你说的，吉姆
I don't read you at all, Jim.
我的意思是…
What I mean is...
要么收到一条信息…
...either a message was received...
只有两种可能
It was one of two things.
要么有人命令我们转向这里
Either someone sent a message diverting us here
要么舰上有人谎称收到信息
or someone onboard the ship lied about receiving it.
那人会不会就是史波克？
Could that someone be Mr. Spock?
吉姆，先别管我们有多了解史波克
Jim, forgetting how well we both know Spock,
他是瓦肯人，不可能说谎
the simple fact that he's a Vulcan means he's incapable of telling a lie.
他也有一半是人类
He's also half human.
那一半是完全遮掩起来的
And that half is completely submerged.
行为举止像人类
To be caught acting like us
甚至像人一样思考会让他尴尬
or even thinking like us would completely embarrass him.
有人在扰乱我指挥，扰乱我的星舰
Someone's interfering with my command and my ship.
我不知道是谁，但我一定要揪出来
I don't know who it is, but I mean to find out.
就连你，如果我觉得你有这能力，我也要怀疑
Even you. If I thought you had the technical know-how, I'd suspect you.
但你没有，史波克有
But you don't. Spock does.
他不会谎报收到命令
He would not make a false entry.
日志上的假信息与事实不符
There's a false entry in the log now which doesn't jibe with the facts.
- 这你怎么解释？ - 我无法解释
- How do you explain that? - I can't
但怀疑史波克，而不是其他人…
but to question Spock, of all people...
如果事出有因，我可能鲁莽行事，你也是
Me, yes, I could run off half-cocked, given a good reason. So could you.
但史波克不会，这不可能
But not Spock. It's impossible.
麦考伊医生，请向传送控制回话
Dr. McCoy, report to Transporter Control.
- 麦考伊医生，请向传送控制台回话 - 我是麦考伊
- Dr. McCoy to Transporter Control. - McCoy here.
进取号需要你，有紧急情况
You're needed aboard the Enterprise, doctor. Medical emergency.
情况怎样？病了还是伤了？严重吗？
Well, what is it? Sickness, injury? How bad is it?
我们只知道这些，医生，就说要你上舰
That's all we have on it, doctor. Just "needed aboard."
也许有人指头上生了倒刺
Probably somebody discovered a hangnail.
我传送上舰再告诉你，吉姆
I'll beam up and let you know, Jim.
“仅限星际舰队指挥官查看”
"For eyes of Starfleet Command only."
我可以证明是我命令你查看的
I'm certifying I ordered you to read it.
知道这个星球吗？
Know anything at all about this planet?
和大家知道的差不多
What every ship captain knows.
一般手则第7条：任何星舰，在任何情况下
General Order 7: "No vessel, under any condition,
包括紧急情况等，都不能降落在塔罗斯4号星球
emergency or otherwise, is to visit Talos IV."
否则将被判死刑，即唯一的死刑
And to do so is the only death penalty left on our books.
只有舰队指挥官才知道为什么，这个文件也没有说明
Only Fleet Command knows why. Not even this file explains that.
但它提到唯一到过这个星球的地球舰只
But it does name the only Earth ship that ever visited the planet.
进取号
The Enterprise.
由克里斯托弗·派克指挥
Commanded by Captain Christopher Pike.
由半瓦肯人史波克担任科学官
With a half-Vulcan science officer named Spock.
准将！派克舰长不见了
Commodore! Captain Pike, he's gone.
- 我是门德兹，发生了什么事？ - 是星舰进取号，准将
- Mendez here. What is it? - starship Enterprise, commodore.
它正在曲速飞离轨道，拒绝答复我们
It's warping out of orbit. Refuses to acknowledge our signal.
离开了轨道，史波克先生
Out of orbit, Mr. Spock.
没有领航员当值真不习惯啊
Seems strange with no navigator on duty.
进取号知道它要去哪儿，汉森先生
The Enterprise knows where she's going, Mr. Hanson.
- 有人试图与我们通话，长官 - 保持无线电静默，上尉
- Someone's trying to hail us, sir. - Maintain radio silence, lieutenant.
我是大副史波克
This is First Officer Spock.
各位舰员听令
Per Starfleet orders this date,
我现在临时担任进取号指挥官
I've been placed in temporary command of the Enterprise.
虽然我们的目的地保密，但我们的任务相对简单
While our destination is secret, our mission is relatively simple.
星际基地指挥官批准寇克舰长医疗休假
Starbase Command has assigned Captain Kirk medical rest leave
直到我们返航，他的命令是…
until our return. His instructions are...
像听从他本人一样听从我
...that you will obey my orders as you would his.
大副，完闭
First officer out.
怎么回事？
What's going on around here?
谁说吉姆需要疗养？
Who said Jim needed a medical rest leave?
为什么叫我上舰？
And this call about me being needed aboard the ship.
- 我检查了每个地方 - 没有人呼叫过
- I've checked everywhere. - And no one made such a call.
- 是的 - 医生，对不起
- That's right. - Doctor, I regret
他们有事瞒着你
they elected to keep certain things from you.
请你跟我来，好吗？
Will you come with me, please?
到底什么事，史波克？
What is this, Spock?
舰长，你怎么样？
Captain, are you all right?
- 我发现你一直在发信号 - 医生，请等一下
- I see that you're still signalling-- - Doctor, one moment, please.
寇克致麦考伊
Kirk to Dr. McCoy.
我给你录了这条信息，老骨头
I’m recording you this message, Bones,
这样就能避免误会
so there'll be no misunderstanding.
非常抱歉命令你
I’m sorry to have to make it an order.
请你不要向派克舰长提问，以免打扰他
You are not to disturb Captain Pike with any questions.
只需照顾好他
Simply take good care of him.
遵守史波克的每条命令，寇克完闭
Follow Spock's instructions to the letter. Kirk out.
长官，扫描器发现有物体跟踪我们
Sir, scanners report an object following us.
大小有如星际基地的穿梭机
About the size of a starbase shuttlecraft.
- 我们要回头吗？ - 什么都不要做，汉森先生
- Shall we reverse helm? - Take no action, Mr. Hanson.
但是以我们的速度，他们永远赶不上
But at our speed, they'll never catch us.
- 但假如他们想追上我们 - 听我的命令，汉森先生
- But in case they want to reach us-- - You have your orders, Mr. Hanson.
我们不作回应
We'll make no contact.
星际基地穿梭机1号呼叫进取号，请回话
Starbase Shuttlecraft 1 to Enterprise. Come in, please.
进取号，我们是准将门德兹和舰长寇克
Enterprise, Commodore Mendez and Captain Kirk.
如果你们能听到，命令你们回复
If you read me, you are ordered to reply.
在所有紧急频率重复，吉姆
Repeating it on all emergency frequencies, Jim.
史波克正飞往塔罗斯4号，没错
Spock is headed for Talos IV, all right.
很快会摆脱我们
Pulling ahead of us fast.
燃料只剩63.3%
Fuel is down to 63.3.
如果现在回头
If we turn back now, we've just got barely enough
刚好够返回基地
to get us back to the base.
穿梭机呼叫进取号，请回答
Shuttlecraft to Enterprise, come in.
进取号，请回答
Enterprise, come in.
- 资料库电脑 - 连接到传感器
- Library computer. - Lock onto sensors.
测量跟踪进取号的物体
Measure object now following the Enterprise.
计算完成，物体是一艘F级穿梭机
Computed. Object is a class-F shuttlecraft.
钍瑞铌金属外壳，离子动力
Duranium metal shell, ion engine power--
停
Stop.
多久以后穿梭机会因燃料不足
How long before shuttlecraft's fuel supply
被迫返回星际基地？
forces return to starbase?
计算完成
Computed.
穿梭机已经错过了安全返航点
Shuttlecraft is already past point of safe return.
我们以惯性滑行了
We coast.
真该死，都是你
Blast you anyway.
按规定你不能来
You had no right to come along.
R.H.I.P.原则，舰长，“长官有特权”
R.H.I.P., captain. "Rank Hath Its Privileges."
只剩两个小时的氧气
Two hours of oxygen left.
这下好了
Wonderful.
其实我有点希望进取号不要回头救我们
Part of me is hoping that the Enterprise won't come back for us.
如果我们上舰，史波克就完了
We step on that deck, Spock is finished,
被军事审判，蒙受耻辱
court-martialled, disgraced.
如果到了塔罗斯4号，他就死定了
He's dead if he makes it to Talos IV.
他为什么要带派克到那儿？
Why would he want to get Pike there?
指挥部早已宣布塔罗斯…
The Command report stated Talos contained
明显对人类没有利用价值
absolutely no practical benefits to mankind.
史波克有他的理由
Spock would have some logical reason for going.
或许他疯了
Maybe. Maybe he's just gone mad.
我在想穿梭机里是谁
I keep wondering who might be after us in a shuttlecraft,
我认为只有一种可能
and I keep coming up with the same answers.
我猜错了，是吧，史波克先生？
But I can't be right, can I, Mr. Spock?
计算机控制中心，锁定跟踪我们的穿梭机
Computer Control, lock onto shuttlecraft following us.
已经锁定，牵引光束就绪
Locked on. Tractor beam ready.
播放磁带“A-7-B”部分
Go to tape Able-Seven-Baker. Execute instructions.
是舰长吗，史波克先生？
Is it the captain, Mr. Spock?
长官，引擎正在反转
Sir, the engines are reversing.
它自己停了
She's brought herself to a dead stop.
我是你们的大副
This is the first officer speaking.
安全部门，派一个武装小队到舰桥
Security, send an armed team to the bridge.
传送室，准备传送寇克舰长上舰
Transporter room, stand by to beam Captain Kirk aboard.
到那之前
Effective until then,
汉森上尉负责指挥运行
Lieutenant Hanson is in operational command.
- 长官？ - 大副完闭
- Sir? - First officer out.
医生，你是在场的高级官员
Doctor, as senior officer present,
我把自己交由你逮捕
I present myself to you for arrest.
- 什么？ - 罪名…
- You what? - The charge...
是叛变，医生
...is mutiny, doctor.
没人批准我负责指挥
I never received orders to take command.
安全人员报到，史波克先生
Security reporting, Mr. Spock.
医生
Doctor...
史波克先生
Mr. Spock is...
被逮捕了
...under arrest.
- 监禁在船舱内够吗？ - 可以，医生
- Is confinement to quarters enough? - Adequate, doctor.
我不会生事的
I'll make no trouble.
- 那就，把他关起来 - 是的，长官
- Well, confine him. - Yes, sir.
把穿梭机停放在机库甲板，史考特先生
Store our shuttlecraft on the hangar deck, Mr. scott.
直接传送我们上舰
Beam us directly aboard.
好的，舰长，已经锁定
All right, captain. Locked onto you.
- 向您转交指挥权，长官 - 接收指挥权
- Transferring command to you, sir. - Accepting command.
- 史波克先生在哪？ - 在他的舱房里，长官，被拘捕了
- Where's Mr. Spock? - In his quarters, sir, under arrest.
他的舱房？在他做了这些事之后吗，上尉？
His quarters? After what he's done, lieutenant?
舰桥报告舰长，引擎开始运转
Captain from bridge. The engines are coming on.
反转动力，保持位置，告诉指挥者
Reverse power. Hold position. Tell whoever gave those orders--
长官，现在没有人在指挥
Sir, there's nobody giving orders.
史波克先生让计算机控制飞船
Mr. Spock has the computers running the ship.
- 解除计算机控制，乌乎拉 - 我们无法解除，舰长
- Disengage Computer Control, Uhura. - We can't disengage, captain.
船舵没有响应
The helm does not respond.
计算机控制，请回话
Computer Control, come in.
- 我是计算机 - 解除船舵控制
- Computer. - Disengage from helm.
无法遵守
Unable to comply.
我是舰长，使用声控指令
This is the captain. On voice command,
忽略所有相抵触的命令
you will override all contrary instructions.
声控指令：解除船舵控制
Voice command: Disengage from helm.
无法遵守
Unable to comply.
任何类似的企图会让星舰的生命维持系统电路冲突
Any such attempt will cross-circuit vessel's life-supporting system.
计算机控制无法解除
Computer Control cannot be disengaged
除非到达塔罗斯4号星球
until vessel reaches planet Talos IV.
舰长日志，星历3012.4
Captain's log, stardate 3012.4.
虽然我们想尽办法解除计算机控制
Despite our best efforts to disengage computers,
进取号还是向着
the Enterprise is still locked on a heading
神秘的塔罗斯4号星球飞行
for the mysterious planet, Talos IV.
此时，遵照星际舰队一般守则
Meanwhile, as required by starfleet general orders,
史波克少校的初步听证会
a preliminary hearing on Lieutenant Commander Spock
正在召开，在我服役的这些年
is being convened, and in all the years of my service,
这是我面临的最痛苦时刻
this is the most painful moment I’ve ever faced.
听证会现在召开
This hearing is convened.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock...
你知道你有权选择辩护律师吗？
...you're aware of your right to counsel of your choice?
长官，我放弃
Sir, I waive counsel.
而且，我放弃听证会，请求立刻军事审判
Further, I waive rights to this hearing and request immediate court-martial.
请求驳回
Request denied.
我能请问理由吗，舰长？
May I enquire on what grounds, captain?
需要至少三名指挥官，才能审判谋反罪
Mutiny requires a trial board of no less than three command officers.
而现在只有两人的军衔满足要求
Since there are only two of that rank available--
长官，我不得不说
Sir, I must point out
这里三个人有指挥官军衔
that there are three officers of command rank available:
你自己，门德兹准将和克里斯托弗·派克舰长
yourself, Commodore Mendez, and Captain Christopher Pike.
驳回
Denied.
派克舰长是完全无效的
Captain Pike is a complete invalid.
我相信你会发现他还在现役名单上
I believe you'll find he's still on the active-duty list.
我们不忍心让他退休，吉姆
We didn't have the heart to retire him, Jim.
他难住你了，无论他打的什么主意，计划都很完美
He's got you. Whatever he's up to, he's planned it well.
舰长日志，星历3012年6月
Captain's log, stardate 3012.6.
召开普通军事法庭审判
General court-martial convened.
史波克先生再次放弃辩护律师，并请求判决有罪
Mr. Spock has again waived counsel and has entered a plea of guilty.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock,
你明白请求判决有罪
are you aware in pleading guilty
会导致另一项涉及死刑的罪名
that a further charge, involving the death penalty,
必须向你提出指控
must be held against you
如果星舰会飞进塔罗斯星群？
should this vessel enter the Talos star group?
- 是的 - 为什么？
- I am. - Why?
为什么要去或者说带派克舰长去那儿？
What does it accomplish to go there or to take Captain Pike there?
我想知道为什么
I want to know why.
你的提问会记录在案吗，长官？
Are your comments a part of the record, sir?
是，已经被记录了！
Yes, it's on the record!
谢谢，请求打开监视器屏幕
Thank you. Request monitor screen be engaged.
为什么？
For what purpose?
回答您刚才的提问，长官
To comply with the request you just made, sir.
说明我去塔罗斯4号星球的重要性
That I explain the importance of going to Talos IV.
向他提问，他就有机会
By asking him why, you've opened the door
出示任何证据
to any evidence he may wish to present.
显然他早已预谋好了
Apparently what he had in mind.
出示你的证据，打开屏幕
Present your evidence. Screen on.
这是13年前
This is 13 years ago.
进取号
The Enterprise...
和它的指挥官，克里斯托弗·派克舰长
...and its commander, Captain Christopher Pike.
前面肯定有东西，舰长
Definitely something out there, captain, headed this way.
关掉屏幕
Screen off.
克里斯
Chris...
屏幕上真的是你吗？
...was that really you on the screen?
这不可能
That's impossible.
史波克先生，任何星舰都不会有这么详细、完整的飞行记录
Mr. Spock, no vessel makes record tapes in that detail, that perfect.
- 你给我们看的是什么？ - 现在不能告诉你，长官
- What were we watching? - I cannot tell you at this time, sir.
派克舰长，在航行中
Captain Pike, were any record tapes of this nature
制作过此类记录磁带吗？
made during your voyage?
当庭不允许观看
The court is not obliged to view evidence
来源不明的证据
without knowing its source.
除非当庭询问被告原因，准将
Unless the court asks a prisoner why, commodore.
你问过这个问题
You did ask that question.
你的意思是我被诱导了
You mean I was manoeuvered into asking.
你的证据超出了规定
Your evidence is out of order.
我不得不反对，我想继续往下看
I am forced to contest that. I want to see more.
你有这个权利，舰长
You have that right, captain.
但这仅仅是因为被告是你的大副
But just because the prisoner is your first officer
和私下的朋友
and your personal friend...
那与之无关
That has nothing to do with it.
那就好，继续
Very well. Continue.
打开屏幕，史考特先生
Screen on, Mr. Scott.
不，是其他东西，还有东西在前面
No. It's something else. There's still something out there.
就像我说过的，这是13年前
As I stated, gentlemen, this was 13 years ago.
我们在例行巡逻
We were on routine patrol
这时，星舰传感器检测到前方有物体
when the ship's sensors detected something ahead.
刚开始我们不知道它是什么
At first, we were not certain what it was.
它以光速飞来，会撞上我们
It's coming the speed of light. Collision course.
陨石光束（偏导仪）不能偏转它，舰长
The meteorite beam has not deflected it, captain.
- 执行规避措施吗，长官？ - 向前直行
- Evasive manoeuvers, sir? - Steady as we go.
是无线电波，长官
It's a radio wave, sir.
我们正在穿过老式的求救信号
We're passing through an old-style distress signal.
它们被调制成干扰信号，以引人注意
They were keyed to cause interference and attract attention this way.
一艘星舰出现故障并迫降，长官
A ship in trouble making a forced landing, sir.
- 就这些，没有其他信息 - 我获取了方位
- That's it. No other message. - I have a fix.
它来自塔罗斯星群
It comes from the Talos star group.
那么远的地方没有我们的星舰或殖民地
We've no ships or Earth colonies that far out.
他们的呼叫代码与一支科学探险队相吻合
Their call letters check with a survey expedition:
哥伦比亚号星舰
SS Columbia.
它在大约18年前消失在那个区域
Disappeared in that region approximately 18 years ago.
无线电波传到这儿确实需要这么久
It would take that long for a radio beam to travel from there to here.
记录显示塔罗斯星群从未被探索过
Records show the Talos group has never been explored.
有和地球所在太阳系类似的系统，11颗行星
Solar system similar to Earth. Eleven planets.
4号星球似乎是
Number four seems to be...
M级
...Class-M.
大气中含氧
Oxygen atmosphere.
这么说18年后他们可能还活着
Then they could still be alive, even after 18 years.
如果他们从坠毁中幸存下来
If they survived the crash.
我们不去…确定吗？
We aren't going to go... to be certain?
如果没有幸存者的迹象，就不去
Not without any indication of survivors, no.
继续飞往织女星殖民地
Continue on to the Vega Colony
先要照顾好我们的伤病员
and take care of our own sick and injured first.
你负责掌舵，保持当前航线
You have the helm. Maintain present course.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
- 我是博伊斯 - 到我的船舱来一下，医生
- Boyce here. - Drop by my cabin, doctor.
那是什么？
What's that?
我没说我病了
I didn't say there's anything wrong with me.
我知道我们收到了遇难信号
I understand we picked up a distress signal.
是的
That's right.
若不能进一步确认
Unless we get anything more positive on it,
我应该优先考虑本舰人员的安全
it seems to me the condition of our own crew takes precedent.
我想把船医的意见也写进日志
I'd like to log the ship's doctor's opinion too.
我赞同你的意见，当然
Oh, I concur with yours, definitely.
好，很高兴你同意
Good, I'm glad you do,
因为我准备先到织女星殖民地
because we're gonna stop first at the Vega Colony
替换掉需要医治的人员
and replace anybody who needs hospitalization.
而且
And also--
你在里面放了什么，冰块？
What the devil are you putting in there? Ice?
要来杯热马提尼酒吗？
Who wants a warm martini?
你怎么知道我想喝？
What makes you think I need one?
有时
Sometimes
人会向酒保倾诉，而不是医生
a man will tell his bartender things he'll never tell his doctor.
你在想什么？是参宿七的那次战斗吗？
What's been on your mind, Chris? The fight on Rigel VII?
不应该吗？
Shouldn't it be?
我的文书加两人死亡，7人受伤
My own yeoman and two others dead, seven injured.
你没能阻止它吗？
Was there anything you personally could've done to prevent it?
当我看到那些人全副式装，就应该发现问题
I should've smelled trouble when I saw the swords and armour.
相反我却自己闯进堡垒
Instead, I let myself get trapped in that deserted fortress
- 被他们的一个战士攻击 - 你为自己设立的标准
- and attacked by one of their warriors. - You set standards for yourself
高不可及
no one could meet.
你宽以待人，严于律己
You treat everyone onboard like a human being except yourself.
现在你厌倦了，而且…
And now you're tired, and you--
你说对了，我厌倦了
You bet I’m tired.
你猜中了
You bet.
我厌倦了对203人的生命负责
I'm tired of being responsible for 203 lives,
我也厌倦了考虑每次任务是否危险
and I’m tired of deciding which mission is too risky and which isn't,
谁参加外遣队，谁不参加
and who's going on the landing party and who doesn't.
谁能活
And who lives.
谁要死
And who dies.
我受够了，菲尔
Oh, I’ve had it, Phil.
准备接受我的建议，去休假？
To the point of finally taking my advice, a rest leave?
准备考虑辞职
To the point of considering resigning.
然后做什么？
And do what?
首先，回家
Well, for one thing, go home.
美丽的小镇，周围有50英里的开阔草地
Nice little town with 50 miles of parkland around it.
还记得我说过有两匹马吗？
Remember I told you I had two horses?
我们过去经常带着食物整天在外面骑行
We used to take some food and ride out all day.
听起来激动人心
Oh, that sounds exciting,
每天骑马出去野餐
ride out with a picnic lunch every day.
我是说这只是可能去的地方之一
I said that's one place I might go.
或者去轩辕十四或猎户座殖民地经商
Or I'd go into business on Regulus or in the Orion Colony.
你做个猎户座商人，贩卖绿皮肤女奴？
You, an Orion trader, dealing in green animal-women slaves?
关键这不是唯一的生活方式
The point is that this isn't the only life available.
宇宙所有的东西都可供选择
There's a whole galaxy of things to choose from.
你不能
Not for you.
一个人要么接受命运
A man either lives life as it happens to him,
勇敢面对并战胜它，要么他
meets it head-on and licks it, or he...
逃避命运，开始退缩
...turns his back on it and starts to wither away.
现在你在用医生口气说话，酒保
Now you're beginning to talk like a doctor, bartender.
你自己选择
You take your choice.
我们都要面对两种人
We both get the same two kinds of customers:
活人和死人
The living and the dying.
我是史波克，我们收到了后续信息，长官
Mr. Spock here. We're intercepting a follow-up message, sir.
塔罗斯星球上有幸存者
There are crash survivors on Talos.
坠毁后11人幸免于难
"Eleven survivors from crash.
重力和氧气都可供生存
Gravity and oxygen within limits.
能找到食物和水源，但除非…
Food and water obtainable, but unless..."
信息到这儿就没了，长官
The message faded at that point, sir.
打开内部广播
Address intercraft.
系统已打开
System open.
我是舰长
This is the captain.
我们将要驶向塔罗斯星群
Our destination is the Talos star group.
曲速7
Our time warp, factor 7.
航线计算完闭，并显示于屏幕
Course computed and on the screen.
已通知各层甲板，长官
All decks have acknowledged, sir.
出发
Engage.
关掉屏幕
Screen off.
史波克先生，我为你的技术所折服
Mr. Spock, I’m truly amazed at your technical prowess
用某种方法创造出这些内容
in somehow manufacturing all this.
我很佩服你的想像力
I congratulate you on your imagination.
但这是宇宙法庭，不是电影院
But this is a court of space law, not a theatre.
舰长，请告诉法庭这不是想像
Captain, please tell the court this is not imagination,
也不是什么精心制作的影像
nor some clever photographic record.
我们看到的是13年前真实发生的事情吗？
Are we seeing the actual events of 13 years ago?
是的，先生们，屏幕上展示的，确有其事
Yes, gentlemen, on that screen, as it happened,
克里斯托弗·派克舰长在塔罗斯4号上难以置信的经历
the incredible experience of Captain Christopher Pike on Talos IV.
如果看过所有这些，当庭还要求星舰回头
If, after witnessing this, the court wishes to turn this vessel back,
我会让星舰恢复手动控制
I will release this ship to manual control.
你没有权利讨价还价，这太荒唐了
You're in no position to bargain. This is ridiculous.
他谋反，盗走你的星舰，诱拐了派克舰长
This man mutinied, stole your ship, abducted Captain Pike.
- 我觉得，这太过分了 - 我们还没听完故事
- For me, this has gone far enough. - We still haven't heard the story.
- 我同意继续 - 我不同意，陷入僵局
- I vote to continue. - And I vote we do not. Deadlock.
没有陷入僵局
It's not a deadlock.
审判委员会还有一人有表决权
There's still one member of the trial board to be heard from.
那好吧，派克舰长
Very well. Captain Pike,
就看你了，这种情况下我们还要继续吗？
it's up to you. Do we continue under these conditions?
是的
Yes.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplemental.
史波克先生以谋反罪被起诉
Mr. Spock, on trial for mutiny,
庭上被迫接受非常规的证据
has forced the court to accept unusual evidence.
在我们的屏幕上
On our monitor screen,
舰长派克和进取号，正在驶向
the voyage of Captain Pike and the Enterprise
所有星系中被禁止的地方
to the one forbidden world in all the galaxy.
打开屏幕
Screen on.
我们已经进入轨道，长官
We've settled into orbit, sir.
地质学实验室的报告完成了，舰长
Geological lab report complete, captain.
- 初步的实验测量结果出来了，长官 - 光谱分析？
- Preliminary lab survey ready, sir. - Spectography?
读数显示大气为氮氧混合，长官
Our reading shows an oxygen-nitrogen atmosphere, sir,
有大量的惰性元素，但是安全的
heavy with inert elements, but safe.
- 重力？ - 地球的0.9倍
- Gravity? - Zero-point-nine of Earth.
舰长，检测到反光，来自星球表面
Captain. Reflections, sir, from the planet's surface.
我发现，它们的偏振性就像金属颗粒
As I read it, they polarise out as rounded metal bits.
- 有可能是太空船的部分外壳 - 召集一组6人的外遣队
- Could be parts of a spaceship hull. - Equip a landing party of six.
- 你想上去吗？ - 是的，长官
- You feel up to it? - Yes, sir.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
抱歉，大副，这个星球信息太少
Sorry, Number One. With little information on this planet,
必须留下最有经验的军官掩护我们
we'll have to leave the ship's most experienced officer here covering us.
当然，长官
Of course, sir.
虽然没有发现危险，但我们不能冒险
There's no indication of problems, but let's not take any chances.
是的，长官，左边有个峡谷
Yes, sir. There's a canyon to the left.
我们把你们放在那儿，可以完全隐蔽
We can set you down there completely unobserved.
长官
Sir.
他们是人
They're men.
他们是人类
They're humans.
我是联邦星舰进取号的舰长，克里斯托弗·派克
Captain Christopher Pike, United Spaceship Enterprise.
我是美洲大陆学会的西奥多·哈斯金斯博士
Dr. Theodore Haskins, American Continent Institute.
地球还好吗？
Is Earth all right?
还是一样，你可以很快看到
The same old Earth, and you'll see it very soon.
而且回去时快得让你无法想像
And you won't believe how fast you can get back.
时间界限已经被跨越，我们的新船能…
Well, the time barrier's been broken. Our new ships can...
这是维娜
This is Vina.
她父母双亡，她是在我们坠落前出生的
Her parents are dead. She was born almost as we crashed.
- 呼叫进取号 - 外遣队，请回话
- Enterprise. - Landing party, come in.
我们准备传送幸存者和他们的物品上舰
We'll begin transporting the survivors and their effects up to you very shortly.
房间已经准备好了，长官
Quarters are being prepared, sir.
需要我派出侦查和科学小队吗？
Have I permission to send out scouting and scientific parties?
是的，批准
Yes, affirmative on this--
你看起来既健康又聪明，舰长
You appear to be healthy and intelligent, captain.
优质的样本
Prime specimen.
我不明白最后那条信息，舰长
I didn't get that last message, captain.
批准请求
Affirmative on request.
外遣队完毕
Landing party out.
请你原谅她的措词，舰长
You must forgive her choice of words, captain.
她一辈子都和一群老朽的科学家生活在一起
She's lived her whole life with a collection of aging scientists.
打断他们一下，我想完成我的医疗报告
If they can spare you a moment, I'd like to make my medical report.
我想是时候告诉舰长我们的秘密了
I think it's time to show the captain our secret.
他们健康状况非常好，好得难以置信
Their health is excellent, almost too good.
这可以解释
There's a reason for our condition,
但我们怀疑地球接受不了我们的秘密
but we've had some doubt if Earth is ready to learn the secret.
让这女孩带你去看，我们接受你的评价
Let the girl show you. We'll accept your judgement.
你累了，别担心，马上就会好起来
You're tired, but don't worry. You'll feel much better soon.
你看见了吗？
Don't you see it?
这儿和那儿
Here and here.
- 我不明白 - 你会的
- I don't understand. - You will.
你是合适的人选
You're a perfect choice.
舰长！
Captain!
- 我是史波克 - 外遣队，请讲
- Spock here. - Landing party, come in.
这里没有幸存者的营地，大副
There is no survivor's encampment, Number One.
这都是某些陷阱
This is all some sort of trap.
舰长不见了，你能听到吗？
We've lost the captain. Do you read?
- 这是什么？ - 是给门德兹准将的
- What is it? - It's for Commodore Mendez.
- 舰队消息，长官 - 说吧，乌乎拉
Fleet signal for you, sir. Go ahead, Uhura.
门德兹准将，有紧急情况
Commodore Mendez. Urgent.
子空间监视器显示
Subspace monitors show
进取号正在接收塔罗斯4号的信息
Enterprise receiving transmissions from planet Talos IV
这违反了星际舰队的一般手则
in violation of Starfleet general orders.
接收塔罗斯4号的信息？
Receiving transmissions from Talos IV?
那我们刚才观看的…
Then the images we've been seeing are--
- 是来自塔罗斯4号，长官 - 解除寇克的职务
- Are coming from Talos IV, sir. - Captain Kirk is hereby relieved.
命令你担任进取号指挥
You are ordered to assume command of the Enterprise.
必要时瘫痪星舰以阻止进一步接触
Disable vessel, if necessary, to prevent further contact.
由星际舰队指挥科姆素尔签署
Message signed, Comsol, starfleet Command.
史波克先生，你明白关于不与塔罗斯4号接触的命令
Mr. Spock, you're aware of the orders regarding any contact with Talos IV.
你是自寻死罪
You have deliberately invited the death penalty.
你不仅毁了自己，史波克
You've not only finished yourself, Spock,
也毁了你的舰长
but you finished your captain as well.
准将你应该明白舰长并不知情
The commodore must be aware that Captain Kirk knew nothing of this.
你也知道舰长要为
And you're aware that a captain is responsible
所指挥舰只上的所有情况负责
for everything that occurs on his ship.
我命令你恢复星舰的人工操作
I order you to return this vessel back to manual control.
长官
Sir...
我很遗憾地拒绝
...I respectfully decline.
那好吧，你要为此后果负责
Very well. You've earned the consequences.
休庭
This court is in recess.
你知道自己在做什么吗？
Do you know what you're doing?
- 你疯了吗？ - 舰长
- Have you lost your mind? - Captain.
吉姆，求你，不要阻止我
Jim, please don't stop me.
不要让他阻止我
Don't let him stop me.
这关系到你的前途和派克舰长的生命
It's your career and Captain Pike's life.
你必须观看信息的后半部分
You must see the rest of the transmission.
把他关起来
Lock him up.
本集结束
未完待续
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏